live. Like I said, welcome brothers and
sisters to another Wednesday question
and answer where we open up with the ten
commandments that God commanded for the
whole world to keep. Brother James. Yes,
sir. And God spake all these words,
saying, I am the Lord thy God, which
have brought thee out of the land of
Egypt, out of the house of bondage. Thou
shalt have no other gods before me. Thou
shalt not make unto thee any graven
image, or any likeness of anything that
is in heaven above, or that is in the
earth beneath, or that is in the water
under the earth. Thou shalt not bow down
thyself to them, nor serve them. For I,
the Lord thy God, am a jealous God,
visiting the iniquity of the fathers
upon the children unto the third and
fourth generation of them that hate me,
and showing mercy unto thousands of them
that love me, and keep my commandments.
Thou shalt not take the name of the Lord
thy God in vain. For the Lord will not
hold him guiltless that taketh his name
in vain. Remember the Sabbath day, to
keep it holy. Sixth day shalt thou labor
and do all thy work. But the seventh day
is the Sabbath of the Lord thy God. In
it thou shalt not do any work. Thou nor
thy son, nor thy daughter, thy man's
servant, nor thy maidervant, nor thy
cattle, nor thy stranger that is within
thy gates. For in six days the Lord made
heaven and earth, the sea, and all that
in them is, and rested the seventh day.
Wherefore the Lord blessed the Sabbath
day, and hallowed it. Honor thy father
and thy mother, that thy days may be
long upon the land, which the Lord thy
God giveth thee. Thou shalt not kill.
Thou shalt not commit adultery. Thou
shalt not steal. Thou shalt not bear
false witness against thy neighbor. Thou
shalt not covet thy neighbor's house.
Thou shalt not covet thy neighbor's
wife, nor his man's servant, nor his
maid servant, nor his ox, nor his ass,
nor anything that is thy neighbors. I'd
read Exodus 20:es
1-17. May the Lord add a blessing to the
reading of this word. In Jesus name we
pray. Amen. Amen. Amen. So here on
question and answer, you can ask us a
question and we'll answer it according
to the King James Bible. And if we
cannot find the answer, we will seek
further counsel to bring you an answer
at a later time. The questions we will
not answer are the vague and the long
scripture questions as well as the
questions of debate. We are not here to
debate. We are here to spread the true
gospel of Jesus. So please be as direct
as possible with your questions so we
can be as direct as possible with our
answers out of the King James Bible. No
other Bibles or books will be
acknowledged on this program. Also, keep
in mind this is a live stream and you
may begin to send in your questions at
this time. Even questions that pertain
to everlasting life. We just asking that
you keep them to a two scripture maximum
per question. But let me introduce to
you the family that's on the panel this
evening. Got brother Jerome. Rest in
peace. Brother Dre. Good evening,
brother Julius. Good evening everybody.
Brother James, good evening everyone.
Sister Deborah. Good evening, brother
Sean. Good evening. And we have the
guest caller with us and I'm brother
Cornell. Sister, let us begin with the
first question of the evening. All
right. There are several held over
questions that will be answered first
before getting into tonight's
Q&A. Um, Tracy Smith asks, "Can you take
your high blood pressure medicine during
fasting?"
Um, the answer is yes, you can take your
high blood pressure medicine even though
you might be fasting.
Let's go into um
Isaiah the first
chapter, brother James. Isaiah the first
chapter and verse
18 and just read the
first 11 words of that verse. Go ahead.
Isaiah 1 verse 18 says, "Come now and
let us reason together, sayeth the
Lord." Yeah. So I just wanted to go and
read that because it is good reason for
you to take your blood pressure medicine
if you are on it because if you don't
take it it can cause you to have a trip
to the emergency room. Um sometime
people have strokes, heart attacks and
other things for not taking a blood
pressure medicine. So yeah you can take
your blood pressure medicine while you
are fasting and
um that's all I got on that.
And we hope that that answered your
question as we move on to our next
question. Moving on. Miss Love asks, "Is
it okay to be friends and go places with
a man that's married? No funny business,
just friends."
All right, Brother Dre. No funny
answers. Give it to her straight.
Yeah. Well,
[Music]
um, how about not going with a married
man
places? You know what about his
wife? Is his wife
going? If his wife is not going, why are
you going
places? And no funny business today, but
doesn't say it won't be tomorrow, you
know.
question is, would you want your
husband that you
have to go
places with a
woman that is quote unquote his
friend and no funny business? I don't
think so. So, let's go to Matthew uh
Matthew 7 and we just going to read one
verse there. Matthew 7 and read verse
12.
Therefore, all things whatsoever ye
would that men should do to you, do ye
even so to them. For this is the law and
the prophets. Right? So, you don't you
wouldn't want that. Especially somebody
you didn't know. And if you do know
him, why are you going somewhere with
somebody else's
husband? No, ma'am. Don't do that.
That's all I got.
All right. I like that. I like to have,
you know, I've talked to a lot of guys
because they say, "Well, me and this
this sister's friends and we this and we
that and we study the Bible together." I
said, "Look, if you do that, sooner or
later you going to go beyond studying
the Bible or just hanging out in every
case." And I mean it's more than one.
Everyone has gone beyond
it. You know, it's just like flirting
with the uh
temptation.
No, let let him take his wife. That's
all I have to say.
All right. Hope that answers your
question as we move on for our next one.
Moving on. Miss Wade asks in Luke
15:es
25-31, "What is the mi what is meant by
the statement the father made to the
elder son?"
All right. Luke
15:25-31. What is meant by that
statement, brother Julius?
A lot of scriptures to read. uh Luke 15.
This is a parable and it's really a par
uh it's a parable of the prodigal
son. Go ahead and read it. Uh James Luke
15 read quick 25-31.
Now his elder son was in the field, and
as he came and drew nigh to the house,
he heard music and dancing. And he
called one of the servants, and asked
what these things meant. And he said
unto him, "Thy brother is come, and thy
father hath killed the fattest calath,
because he has received him safe and
sound." And he was angry, and would not
go in. Therefore came his father out,
and intreated him. And he answered, said
to him, answering said to his father,
"Lo, these many years do I serve thee,
neither transgress I at any time thy
commandment, and yet thou never gavest
me a kid, that I might make Mary with my
friends." Now, pay attention to what
we're about to read here. Go ahead. But
as soon as this thy son was come, which
hath devoured the living with harlots,
thou hast killed for him the fatted
calf. The the young man wanted his
inherit uh his inheritance. His father
gave it to him. He went out into the
world and uh live righteously and uh uh
uh um just did whatever he wanted to do
and messed up his inheritance. You read
the whole story on your own. But so now
he finally came to his senses and went
back to his home to his father's house.
Go ahead. And he said unto him, "Son,
thou art ever with me." and all that I
have is thine. You have always been with
me and you ain't never did. You've
always did what I asked you to do.
You've been a a wonderful son.
Everything I got is
yours. Go ahead. It was neat that we
should make Mary and be glad for this
thy brother was dead and is alive again
and was lost and is found. This is a
parable of how the godhead feel about us
who go out there into the world, get all
into sin, recognize our sin, acknowledge
it, and come back and ask for
forgiveness and come back to God. Let me
show you what I'm talking about. That's
Luke uh 15 and just verse 7. Here's your
answer. Luke 15:7. And this is how
summed up what the whole story of this
is all about. Go ahead. I say unto you
that likewise joy shall be in heaven
over one sinner that repented more than
over 90 and nine just persons which need
no repentance. So the son that was
protesting he was just the sick need a
physician not the well. So it was right
for them to rejoice. And we need to get
out in our mind today. We are not
supposed to be upset with people who go
out into the world and sin, but we
supposed to rejoice when they turn from
their sin, turn back to the Lord and
serve him. And it's that is a cause for
celebration. That's all I got.
Yep. That's right. Brother was dead, but
he was alive when he came back. We were
dead and we come now. We got a chance at
everlasting life. What a what a joy.
Yes, sir. Indeed it is. All right. We
hope that answered your question as we
move on to our next one. Next one. V.
Addie asks in Ezekiel 1 verse
16, please explain the will in the
middle of the wheel. Let's go to Ezekiel
1 and
16. And they want some explanation of
the wheel and the middle of the wheel.
When you get there, brother, go ahead
and read it. and the guest caller. We'll
take it from there. Okay. Ezekiel 1:16
says, "The appearance of the wheels and
their work was like unto the color of a
burl, and they found and and they for
had one likeness, and their appearance
at their work was as it were a will in
the middle of a
will." Well, there's nothing to explain.
It says what it says and what it mean I
don't have a clue cuz there's no no
other scripture that tells us what that
is. So if it's nothing written that can
explain it then all we can do is read
what's there and leave it alone. There
ain't nothing to uh uh uh
uh to explain. It says what it says.
Whatever it mean, I don't have a clue.
All
right, we hope that that uh shared some
light for you as we continue to move on
to our next question. Next question.
Ludia Raymond says, "There is a brand
that is named Nike. The name originated
from the goddess of victory. Am I
breaking God's commandments of not
having other gods before him by wearing
clothes of a pagan god?
Right, brother Julius? Nike and pagan
gods. There's a lot of stuff out here.
What say you? I say these are brands and
there are endless brands. These are
brand names and a whole lot of things
get their origins from pagans such as
the days of the week, such as the months
of the year. They're all named after
pagan gods and planets and so on and so
forth. The question is, are you
worshiping it? Are you bowing down to
it? Like Christmas, like Easter, like
Halloween, pagan that people worship,
are you worshiping and bowing down to
it?
No, you got Goodyear tire, the little
the little wing feet. Uh, but the good
but it's a brand but it represents speed
and reliability. You got Dove soap, you
got Starbucks coffee and so on. Just
different brands. Saturn automobile
named after uh Cronis the father of Zeus
but it's a name. It's a brand name. So
it's the same thing. You're not
worshiping it and that's what counts.
That's all I got.
Right. Hope that answered your question
as we move on to our next one. Next one.
Vetty asks, "Can women teach the classes
for the children? Sabbath lessons."
So, can women teach the classes for the
children? And if it's a Sabbath lesson,
guess call them.
Not at the Israel of
God. All right. Your answer to that
question is not at the Israel of God.
No. The you cannot women cannot teach
the classes for the children. All
right. We're going to move on to our
next question. Next question. Christy
Watson says, "The way things are going
in the country now, do you believe we
should be preparing for darker days?"
Way things are going, do we need to
prepare for darker days? Guess
call. I don't know how to prepare for
darker
days. So, what can I tell you? How you
going to do it? which is save food.
You're going to do like the Israelites
did back in the 60s, go off and buy
farms so when things get bad that uh
they could go out on their farm and uh
uh live good. And I used to tell them
all the time that uh if these Gentiles
of the economy go bad and everybody
going to be hungry, you think that these
Gentiles with their tanks and the
automatic weapons going to let a bunch
of Hebrew Israelites sit down on their
farm and eat and live good while the
rest of them starve. So the question is,
how do you prepare for darker days? I
don't have a clue.
All right.
Get up every day. Put on the whole armor
of God. Yes, sir. What was that?
That's all I have to say. Pray to God.
Hope he deliver you. Yep. Good answer.
All right. Hope that answered your
question as we move on to our next one.
Next one. Cool Blue says, "If you're
married and let's say you just now
trying to find God for salvation, but
your spouse don't want no part of it at
all." What do you do? Because I don't
want that spouse.
Brother Dre, what' you say?
Well, you don't put your spouse away.
That's one thing you don't do. Are you
be no different than your spouse who
don't want no part of the truth? Cuz the
Bible don't support that. Let's go to 1
Corinthians the 7th chapter. 1
Corinthians 7 and pick it up at verse
10.
1 Corinthians 7:10 says, "And unto the
married, I command yet not I, but the
Lord, let not the wife depart from her
husband." Mhm. But and if she depart,
let her remain unmarried, or be
reconciled to her husband, and let not
the husband put away his wife. So
whatever the case may be, if something
happens and you all separate, it says,
"Hey, you know, do not rem, it says
remain unmarried. I'll be reconciled to
your husband and the husband don't put
away his wife." Go ahead, brother. But
to the rest speak I, not the Lord. If
any brother hath a wife that believeth
not, and she be pleased to dwell with
him, let him not put her away. Go ahead.
And the woman which hath an husband that
believeth not, and if he be pleased to
dwell with her, let her not leave him.
So if you got a husband and he be
pleased to dwell with you and he don't
believe, don't leave your husband. This
is what the book is telling you. Go
ahead, brother. For the unbelieving
husband is sanctified by the wife, and
the unbelieving wife is sanctified by
the husband. Else were your children
unclean, but now are they holy. That's
right. Go ahead. But if the unbelieving
depart, let him depart. A brother or
sister is not under bondage in such
cases. But God has called us to peace.
So if if the husband depart, let him
depart. God has called us to peace in
that case. But don't you do nothing to
drive him away or you will be no
different than them because the Lord is
calling for you to walk in
righteousness. Read the next verse,
brother. Go ahead. For what knowest
thou, oh wife, whether thou shalt save
thy husband? Or how knowest thou, oh
man, whether thou shalt save thy wife?
That's right. Cuz by you walking in
righteousness, maybe he'll pick it up,
but maybe he won't. But you don't turn
and go the other way neither. Let's go
to one more place. Let's go to 1 Timothy
4. 1 Timothy 4 and we going to pick it
up at verse 13. And we're going to skip
1 Timothy 4 and 13. And we'll skip.
Okay. Go ahead, brother. till I come
give attendance to reading to
exhortation to doctrine. That's what you
do. You give attendance to reading to
exhortation and doctrine. Skip down to
verse 15. Go ahead. Meditate upon these
things. Give thyself holy to them that
thy profiting may appear to all. That's
right. Go ahead. Take heed unto thyself
and unto the doctrine. continue in them.
For in doing this, thou shalt both save
thyself and them that hear thee. Hey,
you might set an example by living this
thing. You said you wasn't before. You
came into it. Maybe the Lord might prick
his heart when he see you walking in
this thing. So, continue to walk in this
thing and be faithful and patient with
your
husband. That's all I got.
All right, thank you for that. Hope that
answered your question as we move on to
our next question. Moving on, Cassie Lee
says in Second Kings 2 verse 1, it
states that the Lord would take Elijah
up to heaven by a whirlwind. But in John
3:13, it states that no man has ascended
to heaven. Was that a misprint in second
Kings?
Uh, no it wasn't. And actually, both of
those are accurate. So, let's go into
that uh second
Kings. Let's go into that second Kings
2 and let's pick it up at that verse one
there, brother. 2 Kings 2 and 1. Go
right ahead. And it came to pass when
the Lord would take up Elijah into
heaven by a whirlwind that Elijah went
with Alicia from Gilgal. All right. So
this heaven here that we talking about
when it comes to Elijah, the first
understanding that you need is that
there's three heavens. There's the earth
and there's the once you off the earth
all the way to the outer planets, the
space, the sky, the clouds, all of that
is the second heaven and then there's
the third heaven where the father, the
son, and the holy angels dwell. So skip
down to verse um nine and read. Go
ahead. And it came to pass when they
were gone over that Elijah said unto
Elisha, "Ask what I shall do for thee
before I be taken away from thee." And
Elisha said, "I pray thee, let a double
portion of thy spirit be upon me." Mhm.
And he said, "Thou hast asked a hard
thing. Nevertheless, if thou see me when
I am taken from thee, it shall be so
unto thee. But if not, it shall not be
so. All right. And it came to pass as
they still went on and talked that
behold, there appeared a chariot of fire
and horses of fire, and parted them both
aunderder, and Elijah went up by a
whirlwind into heaven. All right. So, it
says here that Elijah went up by a
whirlwind into heaven. That was just
merely up and off the ground. And that
is one of the heavens, the second one
that we were talking about. But let's go
into 2 Chronicles 21. Go to 2 Chronicles
the 21st chapter.
And when you get there, let's pick it up
at that verse 12. And let's just show
that even though Elijah was taken up and
departed away from Elitia, he was found
to be somewhere else, just another place
on the earth. Let's read that 21 and
verse 12. Go ahead. And there came a
writing to him from Elijah the prophet,
saying, Thus said the Lord God of David
thy father, because thou has not walked
in the ways of Jehoshaphat thy father,
nor in the ways of Essa, king of Judah.
So we see here that after he was taken
up, he was found somewhere else and he
wrote and sent to Jehoram, another
brother. He wrote him a letter. So we
know that he was still here on the
earth. Now let's go into um that John 3
and 13. John 3 and 13.
Okay. And this here you can take it
exactly as as it is written because
there's no adding to or taking
away three and 13 because they were
asking about this part here trying to
match heaven to Elijah. Go ahead. And no
man had ascended up to heaven but he
that came down from heaven even the son
of man which is in heaven. So, and no
man have ascended up. No man has ever
went up to heaven, but he that came down
from heaven, which is the one that came
to die for the sins of the whole world.
He's the only one that came down from
heaven. And he is the only one that
ascended back up. So, no man ever has
ascended up to heaven. And that is a
popular doctrine that's being taught,
but we are here to correct it. So, that
is not true. Now, turn over to John 8.
John 8 and let's pick it up brother at
that verse 20 there.
John 8 and verse 20
says these words spake Jesus in the
treasury as he taught in the temple and
no man laid hands on him for his hour
was not yet come. This is the one that
ascended down and came to die for the
sins. Go ahead. He's speaking it. Go
ahead. Then then said Jesus again unto
them, I go my way, and ye shall seek me,
and shall die in your sins. Whether I
go, ye cannot come. Oh, and whether he
go, ye cannot come. He let it be known.
He's talking about when he is sitting
back at the right hand of the father, ye
cannot come there. Go ahead. Then said
the Jews, will he kill himself? because
he saith, "Whether I go, ye cannot
come." Uh-huh. Here's the one that
ascended. Go ahead. And he said unto
them, "Ye are from beneath, and I am
from above. Ye are of this world. I am
not of this world." All right. So, he
was letting it be known that you cannot
go because he's the one came down. He's
the only one that would be going back
up. No other man or woman has ever made
that journey. One more verse there.
Isaiah 57 and 15. And that'll be it.
Isaiah 57 and 15. And here is that third
heaven that we made mention about. Let's
see who's there. Go ahead. All right.
Isaiah 57 and 15 says, "For thus saith
the high and lofty one that inhabitth
eternity, whose name is holy, I dwell in
the high and holy place with him also
that is of a contrite and humble spirit
to revive the spirit of the humble and
to revive the heart of the contrite
ones." All right. So this is the father
and the son here that are sitting on
thrones in the third heaven. No man has
ever went up there. And that is what was
meant by the heavens that we spoke about
or that the book spoke about and that
second Kings as well as that John
letting you know that no man or woman
has ever been there. And that's all I
got on that.
Did you go to the 11th chapter 2
Corinthians 11 the 12th chapter where
Paul told you there was three heavens.
All right.
Second Corinthians 12 and chapter 12 12
and two 12 second Corinthians 12 right 2
Corinthians 12 and2 says I knew a man in
Christ above 14 years ago whether in the
body I cannot tell or whether out of the
body I cannot tell God knoweth such as
one caught up to the third heaven
So that let you know there's three
heavens. All that happened was uh Elijah
was caught up and he's taken somewhere
on earth and put back down on the earth
which is the first heaven. That's all I
have to say. All right. Hope that
answered your question as we move on to
our next one. Moving on. Uh, Cool Blue
says, "Can you give scripture that
states Jesus will come out of heaven to
earth when it's time and one where God
says he wishes to come to earth himself
to exist with us?" Brother Jerome.
Yes. Let's go to um Revelations
19 and read verse 11- 15.
Okay. Revelation 19 11-15 says, "And I
saw heaven open, and behold, a white
horse, and he that sat upon him was
called faithful and true, and in
righteousness he doeth judge and make
war." His eyes were as a flame of fire,
and on his head were many crowns, and he
had a name written that no man knew but
he himself.
And he was clothed with a vesture dipped
in blood. And his name is called the
Word of
God. And the armies which were in heaven
followed him upon white horses clothed
in fine linen, white and clean. And out
of his mouth goeth a sharp sword, that
with it he should smite the nations, and
he should rule them with a rod of iron.
and he treaded the wine press of
fierceness and wrath of Almighty God.
And so we reading where the Lord is
coming down from heaven back to this
earth and he going to make war with the
nations with the with the spirit that's
coming from his mouth, his
word. And uh let's go to Psalms
132. Psalms 132, read verse 13 and 14.
For the Lord hath chosen Zion. He hath
desired it for his habitation. This is
my rest forever. Here will I dwell, for
I have desired it.
But that's on this earth. He desired to
dwell in Zion. So he going to leave
heaven and he going to come back to this
earth and at the appointed time he going
to set up residence in Jerusalem because
that's Zion and he going to dwell there
for earth. That's on this earth. Okay,
that's all I got on.
All right, thank you for that, brother.
Hope that answered that question as we
move on with the time check. Yes, the
time is
803. Epha says, please explain
Revelations
22:2. The leaves of the tree were for
the healing of the nations. Why will the
nations need healing if everything will
be made new as stated in Revelations
21:5? All right. So, why don't we go to
Revelations 22 and two first dealing
with the leaves of the
trees for the healing of the nations.
And go ahead and read it and guess
caller will take it from there.
Revelation 22:2 says, "In the midst of
the street of it, and on either side of
the river was there the tree of life,
which bear 12 manner of fruits and
yielded her fruit every month, and the
leaves of the tree were for the healing
of the nations."
Okay. and and and the only reason it's
there in the uh uh uh in
Revelation in the Lord's kingdom is
because it's just a relic, something
left over and something to show just
like it was with the ark of the
covenant. Arc of the covenant represent
the Lord's presence because the Lord
wouldn't wasn't uh uh uh was not here
physically with the people that they
could see him. So now the ark of the
covenant was used to show that the the
presence of the Lord. Now let's go and
get an example of this. Let's go into uh
uh Exodus the 25th
chapter. We going to read uh uh 1-10 and
then we going to skip down to 20 and
22. Read it when you get there. Okay.
All right. That is Exodus 25 1-10. And
it says, "And the Lord spake unto Moses,
saying, Speak unto the children of
Israel, that they bring me an offering
of every man that giveth it willingly
with his heart, ye shall take my
offering.
And this is the offering which ye shall
take of them, gold, and silver and
brass, and blue and purple, and scarlet
and fine linen, and goats of hair, and
the ram's skins dyed bread, and badger
skins, and shidum wood. Oil for the
light, spices for oing oil, and for
sweet incense, onx stones, and stones to
be set in the ephob and in the
breastplate. and let them make me a
sanctuary, that I may dwell among them,
according to all that I show thee, after
the pattern of the tabernacle, and the
pattern of all the instruments thereof,
even so ye make it, and they and they
shall make an ark. Now, he said, "Make
me a sanctuary, and I might dwell among
you." Okay, but uh he actually wasn't in
that tabernacle, but go ahead and read.
And they shall make an ark of shamwood.
Two cubits and a half shall be the
length thereof. And a cubit and a half
the breadth thereof, and a cubit and a
half the height thereof.
Okay. Now,
you wanted me to skip down to verse 20.
Uh uh uh 21 and 22. Okay. 21. Verse 21
says, "And thou shalt put the mercy seat
above upon the ark, and in the ark thou
shalt put the testimony that I shall
give thee, and there I will meet with
thee, and I will commune with thee from
above the mercy seat, from between the
two cherubims, which are upon the ark of
the testimony, of all things which I
will give thee in commandment unto the
children of Israel."
So now the ark of the covenant
represents God's presence. Even when
Israel went to war, they always went
with the ark of the covenant. You get
the soldiers would go and then you get
the priest with the trumpets and then
after that would come the ark of the
covenant because the ark of the covenant
represented the presence of God. But now
since the Lord came then he was among
us. So let's go into Revelation.
the uh uh 11th chapter, we're going to
read verses 15-1 17 and then we're going
to skip down to 19. Okay. Revelation 11
15-17 say, "And the seventh angel
sounded, and there were great voices in
heaven, saying, "The kingdoms of this
world are become the kingdoms of our
Lord and of his Christ, and he shall
reign forever and ever." and the four
and 20. That mean he's taken over. He's
on this earth now. Go ahead and read.
And the four and 20 elders which sat
before God on their seats fell upon
their faces and worshiped God. That let
you know that that was the the Lord's
kingdom because the four and 20 elders
are dead. The 24 elders are dead and
they among most of the people that in
the first resurrection going to meet the
Lord. So now that mean they're on earth.
This is the Lord's kingdom. But go ahead
and read 17 says, "Saying, we give thee
thanks, oh Lord God Almighty, which art
and was and art to come because thou
hast taken to thee thy great power and
has reigned."
And now he's ruler. Go ahead. Verse 19
says, "And the temple of God was open in
heaven, and there was seen in his temple
the ark of his testament, and there were
lightnings and voices and thunderings
and an earthquake and great
hell." Now, so this ark of the covenant
was with Israel because the Lord wasn't
there because it represented his
presence. But now, once the Lord is here
and you got the temple there, you still
had the ark of the covenant. Now the ark
of the covenant is in the temple. It
can't it don't have to represent the
presence of God of the Lord because the
Lord is already here. But it's just a
relic a reminder showing what happened
in the past. God just decided to keep
that just like he decided to let the
trees uh with the healing uh
leaves because uh they ain't going
because Revelation tell you that there
ain't going to be no more sickness,
ain't going to be no more death. So you
don't need them. do it just like a a
relic a
momento just like it is with the ark
that will be with the ark of the
covenant that represent the presence of
God. But why do he need something to
represent his presence when he's
dwelling among us? That's all I have to
say.
All right. Hope that answered your
question as we move on to our next
question.
Next one. Hannah says, "How did the
Israelites survive the great tribulation
and Jesus' wrath in order to be alive
and gathered?"
Julius,
the Lord delivers her. He He delivers
you. He marks you. He seals you. And he
warns you on how to
escape. Let's go to um and and it's
nothing new. is something very old.
Let's go to uh to Ezekiel the ninth
chapter, brother James. Ezekiel the 9th
chapter. And when you get
it, pick it up at verse 4. Ezekiel 9 and
4. We going to read 46. Go ahead when
you get it. And the Lord said unto him,
"Go through the midst of the city,
through the midst of Jerusalem, and set
a mark upon the foreheads of the men
that sigh, and that cry for all the
abominations that be done in the midst
thereof." Set a mark upon uh set a mark
upon the people that sick and tired of
what's going on. Go ahead. And to the
others he said in mine hearing, "Go ye
after him through the city and smite.
Let not your eyes spare, neither have ye
pity." Go ahead, James. Say, "Slay
utterly, old and young, both maids and
little children and women, but come not
near any man, upon whom is the mark, and
begin at my sanctuary." Then they began
at the ancient men which were before the
house. He said, "But don't come near
those that are marked, who are
uh wishing this thing and all the stuff
and and and they hate the evils and
stuff that's going on." Now let's take
it to the New Testament. Revelation
chapter
7. Back then he called it a mark. Now
let's look at what he call that seven.
Revelation 7 and verse 1 through3. Go
ahead. And after these things, I saw
four angels standing on the four corners
of the earth, holding the four winds of
the earth. These are the nations. These
are the these are the nations uh uh of
the world. Go ahead. Especially Go
ahead. That the wind should not blow on
the earth, nor on the sea, nor on any
tree. Uhhuh. And and I saw another angel
ascending from the east, having the seal
of the living God. And he cried with the
And he cried with a loud voice to the
four angels to whom it was given to hurt
the earth and the sea, saying, "Hurt not
the earth, neither the sea nor the
trees, till we have sealed the servants
of our God in their foreheads." So now
these during the great tribulation in
that era going to be sealed. But now,
how do we escape? Uh let's go to Psalm
91st chapter.
This is how you seal yourself. This is
how you mark yourself today. Psalm 91,
we going to read verse one in verse 11.
Go ahead, James. He that dwelleth in the
secret place of the most high shall
abide under the shadow of the almighty.
This secret place is today we call it
the wilderness. Skip down to verse 11.
Go ahead. for he shall give his angels
charge over thee to keep thee in all thy
ways. So the Lord going to protect us in
the wilderness. That's why when you read
the whole chapter, you going to see all
kind of carnage and warfare all around.
It's going to be global, but then it
going to come near you because now you
have been taught properly. You read the
book, you understand what a secret place
of the Lord is, and you know when to
flee and where to go to. That's all I
got. I hope that helped.
All right, hope that answers your
question. As we move on to our next
question, next question. Israel Lonear
says in Psalms 1:es 4 and 5, everyone is
going to be judged. So, who are these
that will not stand in the judgment, nor
in the congregation of the righteous?
All right, brother Jerome.
Um, let's go read it. Psalms
1 verse four and
five. Okay. Psalms 1 verse4 and 5 says,
"The ungodly are not so, but are like
the chaff which the wind driveth away."
Therefore, the ungodly shall not stand
stand in the judgment, nor sinners in
the congregation of the righteous.
Okay? when when you read
um 2
Corinthians chapter 5 verse 10 that let
you know you know that the the people
that stand in judgment when they come up
in that uh second
resurrection it's not going to just be
the ones that's written in the book of
life by determination of the Lord that's
sitting on the white throne it's going
to be those that's not written in the
book of life that's going to being
standing before him too that's not
written in the book of life. So that's
why I know this this verse don't mean
that they not going to be standing
there. They going to be standing there.
They just it's just going to be
determined that they ain't going to make
the cut. In other words, they name not
going to be found in the book of life
while they standing there on judgment
day. And it's going to be determined
that it's going to be determined that
they going to have to go to the lake of
fire. Okay. So now let's go to uh Isaiah
chapter 8 read verse 10.
Okay. Isaiah verse 10 says take counsel
together and it shall come to not. Speak
the word and it shall not stand for God
is with us. Yeah. See whatever they
determine it ain't going to stand. I was
just showing you that. That's another
way to define how the word it is it they
shall not stand is defined the same way.
They ain't going to make it. It ain't
it's going to come to nothing. Okay.
Just like they ain't going to make it in
judgment day. It's going to be
determined that they going to have to go
to the lake of fire. Okay. So now one
more place. Let's go to Matthews 25.
Mhm.
And read verse 32 through34. And we're
going to skip. Okay. Matthew 25
32-34 says, "And before him shall be
gathered all nations, and he shall
separate them one from another, as a
shepherd divideth his sheep from the
goats." Yeah. And that's going to be
going on for a thousand years. But when
it's over, I mean, but there's going to
be a judgment day. Okay, go ahead and
read. And he shall set the sheep on his
right hand, but the goats on the left.
Okay. Then shall go ahead. Go ahead.
Then shall the king say unto them on his
right hand, "Come ye blessed of my
father, inherit the kingdom prepared for
you from the foundation of the world."
[Music]
Now, these are the ones that's
considered the righteous. Okay?
like was uh like was mentioned in Psalms
1 verse4 and 5. It talked about the
righteous. They ain't going to stay they
to stand with the righteous because the
righteous going to be written in the
book of life. The unrighteous not going
to be in there. Okay, skip down. Read
verse
41. Then shall he say also unto them on
the left hand, depart from me, you
cursed, into everlasting fire, prepare
for the devil and his angels. Uh-huh.
One more verse. Verse 46.
And these shall go away into everlasting
punishment, but the righteous into life
eternal. Yeah, that's all I got.
Right. So, save yourself from this unto
generation. All right, we're going to
move on to our next question.
Next question. Nephitus says in Daniel
12:12, "Blessed is he that waiteth and
come to the number of days listed here.
These days seems to be past the time of
the three and a half years. Do we know
what this time period represents?"
All right. Looks like it starts off in
Daniel 12 and
12. When you get there, brother, read
that in the guest caller. I take it from
there.
Daniel 12:12 says, "Blessed is he that
waiteth and come to the thousand 305 and
days. All right, guest caller.
Okay. Might be having some technical
difficulties.
So, what we'll do, sister, we'll um put
that on hold. And how about going into
new territory?
Uh all right. Um we are now into
tonight's Q&A for Wednesday, March the
26, 2025.
Mark Robinson
says, "Can we address the Daniel fast
and what fasting truly means?"
All right, the Daniel fast and what does
fasting truly mean, Brother Julius?
The definition of fasting, a biblical
fast is when you deny yourself or
abstain from food, water or pleasure.
Now, people read Daniel the first
chapter uh and they say to Cornel that
well you know Daniel uh fasted in the
first chapter. That was not a fast.
Daniel would not eat with Nebuchadnezzar
menu. But then if you read the whole
chapter, Daniel had beans and pulse for
10 days. So that's not a fast. What? Let
me tell you what Daniel did fast. Daniel
9. Daniel 9
and read verse
three. Daniel 9 and verse three. Because
when you are fasting, you are trying to
get God's attention. Okay, go ahead and
read. And I set my face unto the Lord
God to seek by prayer and supplication
with fasting and sackcloth and ashes. So
now let me show you now back up to the
sixth chapter of Daniel, brother James.
Okay. Daniel 6. And Darius the king
prayed and fasted for Daniel while he
was in the lion's king. Daniel 6 and
read verse 18, my brother.
Then the king went to his palace and
passed the night fasting. Neither were
instruments of music brought before him.
And he slept went from him and his sleep
went from him. So he just went to bed
and prayed and fasting and he couldn't
sleep all night. No music, no pleasure,
no food, no water. Let's go and look at
somebody famous who fasted. Somebody
very famous who fasted. Let's go to
Esther. Let's go to
Esther.
Man, the book of Esther. And let's go to
Esther the 4th
chapter and pick it up at verse 15 and
16. When you get it. Okay, brother
James, go ahead. Esther
4:15-16
says, "Then Esther bade them return more
Then Esther bade them return Mori this
answer. Go and tell Mori what I to do
what I tell them to do. Go ahead. Go
gather together all the Jews that are
present in Shushan and Fashi for me."
Uhhuh. "And neither eat nor drink three
days, night or day. I also and my
maidens will fast likewise and so will I
go into the king which is not according
to the law and if I perish I perish. So
Esther and all the Jews fasted for three
days and three nights. No drink, no
eating, no pleasure because they are
really seeking the Lord to petition to
keep the Jews from being killed. Now my
final place, brother Cornell, let's go
to
Exodus. Exodus the 34th
chapter. This is Let me show you a fast
up fast. Exodus
34. And when you get it, James, we going
to read verses 27 and 28. You see what
the people call fasting today? Well, I'm
not going to eat anything. I'm just
going to eat a little this right here.
I'm not going I'mma give up this and I'm
going to give up that. I'm just gonna
eat a little. No, that is a diet. You're
dieting. A biblical fast is to deny
yourself of food, water,
pleasure. 34 Exodus
34:27-28, my brother, go ahead. And the
Lord said unto Moses, "Write thou these
words, for after the tenor of these
words, I've made a covenant with thee
and with Israel." Uh-huh. And he was
there with the Lord 40 days and 40
nights. He did he did neither eat bread
nor drink water. Uhhuh. And he wrote
upon the tables the words of the
covenant the ten commandments. Moses was
up in Mount Si 40 days and 40 nights.
Didn't eat, didn't drink, no pleasure.
Up there getting the commandments in the
spirit and on in the presence of the
Lord God of Israel. That is a biblical
fast. That's the best I can do. Corno,
right? Thank you for that, brother. Hope
that answered that question. As we move
on to our next one,
next question. Time out. Houston says,
"If Joseph is not Jesus biological
father, why do Matthew and Luke both
give his
genealogy? And why does Matthew trace
Jesus lineage through Solomon while Luke
traces it through Nathan?
All right. Bel Jerome got a little bit
extra added into that question. Can you
shed some light?
Um, well, when you're dealing with Luke,
it's not really tracing Jesus's
lineage. It's tracing Joseph's
lineage. That's why it says oppose the
son
uh of the Lord. But we know he not
really he he not really the father of
the Lord. We know that. That's what I'm
trying to say. So when he started
tracing Joseph, it wasn't tracing Jesus
there. It was tracing Joseph and it
traces to
Nathan which is son of David.
But Solomon is also the son of David.
They in the same
generation, Nathan and Solomon. They
they the
children of uh David. Okay. Now, in
Matthew's that's tracing Jesus by way of
the prophecy of him being the seed of
Abraham on down to
Solomon. Okay. So,
uh, that's that's all I got on that. You
know, when you when you read that, he
not tracing Jesus in that Luke, but he
tracing Jesus in the in the Matthew by
way of the seed of Abraham to Solomon.
That's all I got.
All right. Thank you for that. Hope that
answered that question. Guest caller,
you still with us?
All right. So I will move forward to the
next question after that. All right. All
right. So Tina Ray
asks, "Are Jehovah
witnesses mentioned in the Bible? And if
so, what does this say about them?
All right, brother Dre, they asking
about Jehovah Witnesses. What you say,
brother? Well, the group called Jehovah
Witnesses now. They call themselves
that. They were started by Charles Taz
Russell in the
1870s and he first established the group
as Zion's
Watchtower Track Society in
1881. In 1910 they became International
Bible Students of Association.
after
1910 later on uh under uh Rutherford
which is another one of their leaders
who took over after Charles Taz Russell
they uh changed their name to Jehovah
Witnesses and so they changed their own
name to that but does the Bible speak of
them as Jehovah Witnesses?
No, but the Bible does speak of Jehovah
Witnesses. Now, what they'll do is
they'll go to Isaiah 43 and we're going
to go there and see who this is talking
about. So, let's turn over to Isaiah 43
and we're going to read verse one.
Isaiah
43 and verse one. Go ahead, brethren.
But now thus said the Lord that created
thee, oh Jacob, and he that formed thee,
O Israel, fear not, for I have redeemed
thee. I have called thee by thy name,
thou art mine. Now he's talking to
Israel. And he's
saying that created thee, oh Jacob, and
formed thee, oh Israel, I have called
thee by thy name, thou art mine. Skip
down to verse 10. Go ahead. Ye are my
witnesses, sayaeth the Lord.
And my servant whom I have chosen, that
ye may know and believe me, and
understand that I am he. Before me there
was no God formed, neither shall there
be any be after me. That's right. So,
Israel is God's witnesses are Jehovah's
Witnesses, not this organization that
name themselves that name under
Rutherford in
1931. Skip down to verse 15, brother. Go
ahead. I am the Lord, your holy one, the
creator of Israel, your king. That's
right. So, this is talking about Israel.
So that's who the true witnesses of
Jehovah are. Israel, not this
organization that was formed that
changed their name a few times and under
Rutherford adopted the name Jehovah
Witnesses. I hope that helps.
All right. Yes, sir. That was some good
light there, brother. Hope that answered
their question. as we continue to move
on. Guest caller, are you with us?
Working on it.
All right, let's uh continue to um move
on to our next question. Uh yes, she
also asks, "How do we properly worship
God? Is there a right or wrong way? What
does it entails one to do?
Well, first thing you should do is uh be
seeking after the Lord with all your
heart, all your mind, and all your soul.
And when you locate him, you keep his
commandments and serve him with all your
heart. Now, let's go into that John the
19th chapter. John
19. And we'll get to John 19.
Let's pick it up there at that verse uh
16 I believe is what I want. John
19. Maybe that's not what I mean there.
Let's go into I'm sorry. Let's go into
John 14. John
14. And let's pick it up at that verse
one. Then we going to do some skipping
and reading.
Okay.
John 14:1 says, "Let not your heart be
troubled. Ye believe in God, believe
also in me." Uhhuh. "In my father's
house are many mansions. If it were not
so, I would have told you. I go to a pl
I go to prepare a place for you." And if
you believe that with all your heart,
then you are supposed to get into that
place that he has prepared for you by
any means necessary. Skip down to verse
six and go ahead. Jesus saith unto him,
I am the way, the truth, and the life.
No man cometh unto the father but by me.
Yeah. So you have to come to Jesus cuz
he came representing the father. Skip
down and let's pick it up at verse 15.
If ye love me, keep my commandments.
There you go. Oh, so that is how you
begin to properly worship God because
you want to have that as a testimony for
you that you have walked in these
commandments of God and that you are
serving him with all your heart. That is
supposed to be one of the pathways to
showing the Lord that you love him. Skip
down and read that verse. Did you read
verse 21 for me?
He that hath my commandments and keepeth
them, he it is that loveth me. And he
that loveth me.
And he that loveth me shall be loved of
my father, and I will love him, and will
manifest myself to him. So if you want
some love from the father and the son,
hey, you keep those.
Yes. Caller, are you with us?
Okay. All right. We'll be
All right. Glad you're back. We'll be
with you in one minute. Okay. So, pick
it up. Read that verse 21 again for me.
He that hath my commandments and keepeth
them, he it is that loveth me. And he
that loveth me shall be loved of my
father, and I will love him, and will
manifest myself to him. So that's what
you do. You keep those commandments, and
you serve the Lord with all your heart,
and you will be fine at the end of the
road. That is a guarantee. Now, let's go
into you was asking even about the wrong
way. Let's go into James the 4th
chapter, James
4. Because a lot of people have heard
about God, even the true and living God
that we are reading about
now. So let's pick it up. Read that
verse seven for me and then we go skip.
Submit yourselves therefore to God.
Resist the devil and he will flee from
you. Yes. And resist all that falsehood
and all that doctrine that will not get
you everlasting life. Stick with this
guy. And read verse 17. Go ahead. Verse
17 says, "Therefore, to him that knoweth
to do good and doeth it not, to him it
is sin." So that will get you in trouble
there. Pretty. You have to make sure
that you serve God with all your heart,
all your soul, and all your might, and
you will be all right at the end of the
road. That is a guarantee. And that's
all I
got. All right. We hope that that
answered your question there. And now,
sister Deborah, we have the guest caller
with us. Can we skip up to that verse
14? That question 14 inhal. Yes. Yes.
Ephatha
says in Daniel
12:12, "Blessed is he that waiteth and
come to the number of days
listed here these days seems to be past
the time of the three and a half years.
Do we know what time period what this
time period represents?"
All right. So they asking about that
Daniel 12 and 12. Let's go there and uh
read it my brother and then the guest
caller would take it from there. Okay.
Daniel 12 and 12 says, "Blessed is he
that waiteth and come to the thousand
305 and 30 days."
Now all they're saying is that you have
s you have survived the great
tribulation because the Lord is going to
come and he going to terminate the uh uh
uh uh beast and the false prophet. That
will be the end of the uh uh uh great
tribulation. Go to Revelation the 19th
chapter and read verse uh uh uh 19.
Okay. Revelation 19 and 19 says, "And I
saw the beast and the kings of the earth
and their armies gathered together to
make war against him that sat on the
horse and against his army."
That's Jesus and all the angels. Go
ahead. And the beast was taken, and with
him the false prophet that wrought
miracles before him, with which he
deceived them that had received the mark
of the beast, and them that worshiped
his image. These both were cast alive
into a lake of fire, burning with
brimstone.
Go ahead.
And the remnant were slain with the
sword of him that sat upon the horse
which swore proceeded out of his mouth
and all the fowls were filled with their
flesh.
Now that's taken down of the beast and
false prophet and which started with the
uh uh with the gentile ruling. Let's go
into Daniel the 7th chapter. Okay, we're
going to read 1 through3 then we're
going to skip.
Okay. Daniel 7:1-3 says, "In the first
year of Belshazzar, king of Babylon,
Daniel had a dream and visions of his
head upon his bed. Then he wrote the
dream and told the sum of the matters.
Daniel spake and said, "I saw in my
vision by night, and behold, the four
winds of the heaven strove against the
upon the great sea, and four great
beasts came up from the sea, diverse one
from another."
Now, that was uh uh Babylon,
Persia, Greece, and Rome. And Rome
supposed
to uh fall and rise 10 times. Now, at
the 10th resurrection, that's when the
Lord's going to come. Skip down to verse
13.
And I saw in the night vision, and
behold, one like the son of man came
with the clouds of heaven, and came to
the ancient of days, and they brought
him near before him.
Who? And there was given him dominion
and glory and a kingdom that all people,
nations, and languages should serve him.
His dominion is an everlasting dominion,
which shall not pass away, and his
kingdom that which shall not be
destroyed.
Go ahead. I, Daniel, was grieved in my
spirit in the midst of my body, and the
visions of my head troubled me. Uh-huh.
I came near unto one of them that stood
by and asked him the truth of all this.
So he told me and made me known the
interpretation of these
things. These great beasts were all four
all four kings which shall arise out of
the earth. There's four kingdoms. There
are four kingdoms that shall arise out
on earth. But then who's going to
terminate? Who's going to take over
after them? Read the next verse. But the
saints of the most high shall take the
kingdom and possess the kingdom forever,
even forever and ever.
Okay? And let's see what his kingdom is.
Skip down to verse 27.
and the kingdom and dominion and the
greatness of the kingdom under the whole
heaven shall be given to the people of
the saints of the most high whose
kingdom is an everlasting kingdom and
all dominion shall serve and obey him.
So that mean if you find
yourself living at that time then you
will go from being ruled over by the
beast and false prophet under great
tribulation until Jesus come and take
down the uh uh uh gentile
kingdom after they rule for three and a
half years. Then the saints, the people
that meet him in the air, they going to
take over the kingdom and the kingdom
going to be ruled righteously. So if you
find if you have come to that day and
you still deal still living in that day,
you are blessed because you have
survived the great tribulation and you
also survived the punishment of
Jesus. Don't have to say. All right.
Thank you for that. We hope that
answered your question, Sister Deborah,
as we resume in our new territory at
question three. Yes. Uh the M King says,
"Can we still cast out demons to heal
people today? Jesus gave his disciples
authority to cast out demons." Matthew
10:1, Mark
16:17. And early Christians did the
same. Acts 16 verse 18.
All right. So they want to know about
casting out demons. Can that be done as
well as healing people today? And the
first one is Matthew 10:11. Let's go
there, brother James.
There you read that verse one, the guest
call. I take it from there. Okay.
Matthew 10:1 says, "And when he had
called unto his 12 disciples, he gave
them power against unclean spirits to
cast them out and to heal all manner of
sickness and all manner of disease."
Okay. Read Acts.
Okay. And that was
Acts what chapter again? Acts 16 verse
18. And we also have Mark 16 verse1 17
was given. Okay.
Acts 16 and 18 says and this did she
many days but Paul being grieved turned
and said to the spirit I command thee in
the name of Jesus Christ to come out of
her. And he came out the same hour.
Okay. Go to Acts.
That was Mark 16. Mark 16 verse1 17.
Okay. And Mark 16 verse1 17 says, "And
these signs shall follow them that
believe. In my name they shall cast they
shall cast out devils. They shall speak
with new tongues.
Okay. The Lord, there's no scripture
where it said the Lord took that away.
So, it's still here. I've never seen it
and I've never uh uh experienced it. But
I tell you one
thing, it's still here. The Lord just
did in dramatic form, but we are doing
it another way. What we doing is we are
casting out demons when they teach them
the truth and the people start walking
in the truth and they develop another
mind start walking in newness of
life. As far as the healing is
concerned, I know that it's one person
we I I know that me and the elders
prayed over and we healed her. I'm not
going to call her name on on this
program. So, it's still here.
They just have to have the faith to do
it, right? That's all I have to say.
Yeah. Thank God that is still here. All
this sickness and disease we got with us
in this present day. Amen.
All right. Hope that answered your
question, Sister Deborah. Our next one
with a time check. Yes. The time is
8:45. Philosophy asks in Genesis
3:15, foretelling of Jesus, is it
considered the first prophecy of Jesus
coming through Mary?
Genesis 3 and 15. And let's open up
these questions here to the panel in our
last 15 minutes here. When you get
there, brother, read that. Genesis
15 and then sister Deborah repeat the
question and then it'll be open to the
panel. Genesis 3:15 says, "And I will
put enmity between thee and the woman
and between thy seed and her seed. It
shall bruise thy head, and thou shalt
bruise his heel."
And the question again was in Genesis 3
uh verse 15 for telling of Jesus. Is
this considered the first prophecy of
Jesus coming through Mary? That's
well this this this uh uh uh this
prophecy
uh uh have like uh two women
Oh, yeah. He came through Mary, but but
there's another woman he came through.
Let's go to Revelation the 12th chapter.
Okay. Yes. And we going to read uh verse
one and two. We're going to skip down to
five. Okay. Revelation 12:1 and 2 says,
"And there appeared a great wonder in
heaven, a woman clothed with the sun,
and the moon under her feet, and upon
her head a crown of 12 stars. And she
being with child cried, travailing in
birth and pain to be delivered."
Okay, skip down to verse five.
And she brought forth a manchild who was
to rule all nations with the rod of iron
and her child was called caught up unto
God and to his
throne. Now so this first so we got the
woman is Mary. Yeah, I tell you Jesus
made of a woman and uh and also but the
other woman is
Israel you know a woman clothed in the
sun moon under her feet and the crown of
12 stars that uh uh that's
uh Jacob his wife and his 12 son and
that mean that Jesus came out of Israel
he was a Hebrew Israelite so
now that in um that represent uh uh uh
uh both women, Mary and Israel. That's
all I have to say. All right. Hope that
answered your question as we move on to
our next one. Next question. Daughter of
Judah asks, "Can a person attend IOG
feast and holy day celebrations if
they're not a baptized member? If I'm
visiting from out of town and am able to
attend Sabbath service at IOG, can I be
baptized after service or must I make
plans ahead of time?
Well, we always like to make plans ahead
of time so we can be prepared
um for the baptism because no work goes
into that. But you can attend the feast
if you have not been
baptized. That's fine. As far as the
baptism, we um like to plan and set a
date to give people time to prepare. And
um guest caller, you want to add to
that?
Well, I can't say no more than what you
said.
Okay. All right. So, hey, well, um we
look forward to baptizing you if that's
on your heart. And uh we just ask that
you call the office and put your name on
the list and we'll take it from
there. All right. Hope that answers your
question as we move on to our next one.
Next one. Ni.
Yes. Call. Let me throw in right quick.
You can even take the Passover if you're
not baptized. But if you're a male, you
can't take the Passover if you're not
circumcised.
That is correct.
Everybody, but everybody can attend the
face no matter what your uh uh
uh position is, your situation is. Okay.
Yeah. All right. Good
information. Okay. We're going to move
on to our next question. That's time.
Next question. Yes. Ni Jones asks in
Revelations 3 verse 10, "Was this to the
Philadelphia church only? Does it mean
they won't be persecuted?
Let's go to Revelation 3 and 10. Open up
to the
panel. Revelation 3
and10 and go ahead, brother, when you
get there. Because thou has kept the
word of my patience, I also will keep
thee from the hour of temptation, which
shall come upon all the world to try
them that dwell upon the earth.
Question again,
can you repeat that, Deborah? The
question. Yes, the question is again in
Revelations
3:10. Was this to the Philadelphia
church only? Does it mean they won't be
prosecuted,
persecuted? That's to anybody, no matter
what church they in, if they do what it
said the Philadelphia, then they will
not be persecuted.
That's right. So he will keep thee from
the outward temptation.
That's right. So if you uh if you are
servant of God and you do what the Lord
said, you going to know the signs and
you going to know when it's time to
flee to the wilderness.
You flee to the wilderness, you ain't
going to get touched by a beast of false
prophet. You
will great tribulations.
Yeah. Which is our
temptation. That's right. Yeah. So,
please come on down and serve the Lord.
All right. Our next question. Next
question. Read the Bible daily asks,
"How does Deuteronomy
21 22- 23 apply to Jesus?" I understand
how verse 23 applies. But what about
verse 22? What sin did he commit worthy
of death?
All right, let's go to that Deuteronomy
21. And when you get there, we're going
to pick it up at that verse 22 and 23.
Okay.
Deuteronomy third 20 I'm sorry
Deuteronomy 21 and verse 22 to 23 says
and if a man hath committed a sin worthy
of death and he be put to death and thou
hang him on a tree his body shall not
remain all night upon the tree but thou
shalt in any wise bury him that day for
he that is hanged is a cursed of God
that thy land be not defiled, which the
Lord thy God giveth thee for an
inheritance.
All right. Open to the panel
there, cuz you know, you couldn't leave
a body on a tree.
Well, and he said, "What sin did Jesus
commit?"
Right. What sin did he commit worthy of
death?
He didn't commit one sin worthy of
death.
But let's but uh but let's go and show
you who what he did. Let's go into
Isaiah the 53rd
chapter either 53 or 56. Let me see
where he says that uh with his stripes
we'll seal. 53
53. Yes sir.
Start reading that verse one. Okay.
Isaiah 53 and verse1 says, "Who hath
believed our report? And to whom is the
arm of the Lord revealed?"
For he shall grow up before him as a
tender plant, and as a root out of a dry
ground. He have no form, no comeliness.
And when we shall see him, there is no
beauty that we should desire him.
Mhm. He is despised and rejected of men,
a man of sorrows and acquainted with
grief. And we hid as it were our faces
from him. And he was despised and we
esteemed him not.
Go ahead. Surely he had borne our griefs
and carried our sorrows. Yet we did
esteem him stricken, smitten of God, and
afflicted.
Uhhuh. But he was wounded for our
transgressions. He was bruised for our
He was He was wounded for whose
transgressions? For our transgressions.
Go ahead. He was bruised for our
iniquities. Whose iniquity? Our
iniquities.
Go ahead. The chastisement of our peace
was upon him.
And with his and with his stripes we are
healed.
All we like sheep have gone
astray. We have turned everyone to his
own way. And the Lord hath laid on him
the iniquity of all of us
all. So now Jesus didn't commit one sin
but be but he became the sin offering.
So he died for the sins of man.
Period. Because had he not come and
died, there would be no salvation. So
no, he didn't commit no sin.
Get down to verse 11 and read it.
He shall see of the travail of his soul
and shall be satisfied.
Sorry, verse 10, brother. Okay, go
ahead. Yet it pleased the Lord to bruise
him. He hath put him to grief. When thou
shalt make his soul an offering for sin,
he shall see his seed, he shall prolong
his days, and the pleasure of the Lord
shall prosper in his hand.
So now he committed no sin, but he died
for the sins of everybody else. So
that's what the Lord So the iniquity of
the people is laid upon him. That's all
I have to say. That's it. Can we read
that? Hebrews 4 and 15.
Where? Hebrews 4. And when you get
there, brother, read that um 14 and 15.
Okay. Hebrews 4 14 and 15 says, "Seeing
then that we have a great high priest
that has passed into the heavens, Jesus
the son of God, let us hold fast our
profession. For we have not an high
priest, which cannot be touched with the
filling of our infirmities, but was in
all points tempted like as we are, yet
without
sin. Yep. So that just bags up what the
guest caller was saying that he didn't
commit no sin. No, not
one. Because we needed somebody that was
sin free to die for the sins of the
whole world.
All right, Sister Deborah, we are having
fun and time is ticking. We are down to
our last question or two. Go ahead. Yes,
let's make it or two. Sandra Ellen asks,
"Where does the three days of darkness
take come from?" I'm sure it's not
biblical. Where does the three days of
darkness tail come from?
All right. Does anybody on the panel
have a grasp of where they trying to go
with that question?
I don't even know where what is she
talking about. Right. She needs some
scriptures or something. It sounds like
she's talking about Exodus where they
saw not the Lord about the days of
darkness in the days of Israel in Egypt.
Yeah. They saw not they saw not one
another for three days. Yeah. Bless her.
Let her give some scripture on this so
we'll know exactly what she's asking. So
the next question is from Norman Nicks.
He asks, "Can you explain what Paul
means by
genealogies in Titus 3 verse 9?"
Titus 3 3 verse 9. what he means by
genealogies.
All right, let's go there and read that
and this will be our last
question of the evening. Titus
3. Let's go there, brother. First
Timothy, 2 Timothy, and then Titus.
So, Titus 3 and uh go ahead. But avoid
foolish questions and genealogies and
contentions and strivings about the law
for they are unprofitable and vain.
All right. And they want to know about
the genealogy part.
Yes. What uh explain what Paul mean
meant by these genealogies.
All right. Open to the panel. I I know
that they have a lot of places that have
made much money off of claiming to know
your genealogy and bloodline and where
you came from and background. And I
think one of them is filing for
bankruptcy now, right? Yeah. So, we read
that verse eight.
Yeah. Verse eight. Yeah. It says, "This
is a faithful saying, and these things I
will that thou affirm constantly that
they which have believed in God might be
careful to maintain good works. These
things are good and profitable unto
men." So, in contrast to what was being
said, what we should be doing is making
sure that we maintain good works because
profitable onto man as opposed to
arguing about this
with as it says in verse 10 a man that
is a heretic after the first or second
admonition you reject that man. So know
it says avoid foolish
questions. So maintain good works avoid
foolish questions. That's all it's
saying. And genealogies is just talking
about where people where they came from,
their lineage, right? And actually uh
brother Jerome, you spoke about that too
when we're talking about in Luke and in
Matthews what is written and talking
about the bloodline. Correct?
Yeah. Those are examples of genealogy.
Yes, it is. Exactly. So you going to go
according to that then hey you can bet
on that one but these other ones you
know you can't have no assurityity of
those
and that that previous question is found
in Exodus the 10th chapter about the
three days of darkness in Egypt. Exodus
the 10th chapter vers 22 and 23. It is
not a tale. It actually happened. Okay.
All right. And sister, if you want some
further clarity, brother Julius just
helped you out with where to go exactly
and if that's what you meant, please
resubmit it and we'll address that next
week. So, we hope that that answered the
final question of the evening. Sister
Deborah, time check. The time is 9:03.
All right. We like to thank everybody
from all around the world who joined us
this evening. Amen. We enjoyed partaking
with you in your questions as we supply
the answers. And we want to say until we
all come together again. And if you
submitted a question, don't resubmit it
unless we instruct you to do so. Other
than that, just leave it there. Sister
Te Deborah or take it, put it in
rotation. And we want to say until we
all come together again, please be safe,
be blessed, stay prayed up, and may God
have mercy on us all. As brother James
closes us
out, our Father, which art in heaven,
hallowed be thy name, thy kingdom come,
thy will be done in earth as it is in
heaven. Give us this day our daily
bread. And forgive us our debts as we
forgive our debtors. And lead us not
into temptation, but deliver us from
evil. For thine is the kingdom and the
power and the glory forever. In Jesus
name we pray. Amen. Amen. Amen. Good
night all. Good night. Is that your
phone?